Guide to the School Development Program, Child Study Center, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School Development Program, Child Study Center, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
1967-2008
RU 1111
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
36.85
(240 boxes)
The collection comprises the records of the School Development Program (SDP) which document the efforts of child psychiatrist Dr. James P. Comer and his colleagues at the Yale Child Study Center to research and reform low-achieving schools in New Haven and around the country and overseas. The records consist primarily of training handouts and guides, research reports, and audiovisual recordings.
Yale School Development Program
Biographical / Historical
The School Development Program (SDP) was a K-12 education reform program developed by child psychiatrist Dr. James P. Comer and his colleagues at the Yale Child Study Center in collaboration with the New Haven public schools. First introduced into two New Haven schools in 1968, this research-based program has been implemented in hundreds of schools across the United States and overseas. Grounded in the principles of child, adolescent, and adult development, SDP has worked with educators, parents, and students in individual schools and entire school districts to promote reform in low-achieving schools.
Custodial History
Transferred from the School Development Program, Child Study Center, School of Medicine, 2010.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises the records of the School Development Program (SDP) which document the efforts of child psychiatrist Dr. James P. Comer and his colleagues at the Yale Child Study Center to research and reform low-achieving schools in New Haven and around the country and overseas. The records consist primarily of training handouts and guides, research reports, and audiovisual recordings.
The records are arranged into administrative files, training and professional development program files, research and evaluation files, and audiovisual materials. The records include a very limited amount of material of any type concerning SDP before 1990. The administrative files contain materials that concern SDP generally including a number of strategic plans and the program's newsletter from 1991 to 1998. The training and professional development program files concern the wide variety of national and local initiatives to train educators and schools in the program's developmental approach to change for low-achieving schools. These files consist mostly of training handouts, but also contain a smaller amount of guides for trainers and planning and evaluation materials from individual schools and districts. The research and evaluation files consist primarily of school climate survey reports and other reports concerning the internal review of program methods and implementation by SDP research staff and the external review of SDP by outside groups, largely for funding purposes. The school climate reports summarize survey data from the students, parents, and staff of SDP schools about the general tone of the school and the quality of the relationships among the students and adults in the school building. The audiovisual materials consist of video recordings, and a few audio recordings, of SDP training workshops, meetings, and speeches, but also include a smaller number of video training material produced by SDP and its collaborators.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collection is restricted until 1 January 2043 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.. Contact Public Services for information on requesting access to restricted university records.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: I. Administrative files, 1967-2002. II. Training and professional development programs, 1973-2008. III. Research and evaluation, 1969-2003. IV. Audiovisual materials, 1983-2000.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-E (YRG 27-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Medicine.
Child development -- Research; Child development -- Study and teaching; School improvement programs -- United States; Comer, James P.; Yale School Development Program; Yale University. Child Study Center; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Administrative Files, 1967-2002; Series I
  - Action plans, draft, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Child development: The foundation of education" symposium, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Management team minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National advisory board meeting, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National advisory group meeting, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New district presentation, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "New Haven Public School System Child Study Center proposal", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsline newsletter, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Program brochures, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Project proposals
  - Strategic plans, 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Thirtieth anniversary symposium, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Twenty-fifth anniversary celebration, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Yale Child Study Center, 1911-1999" (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Training and Professional Development Programs, 1973-2008; Series II
  - General
    - Achievement gap conference, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn/New Haven Youth Consortium, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Contract worksheets, 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
    - Contracts, 2001-2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - District entry process, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Fieldbook, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fieldbook drafting, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
    - Alphonse Fletcher Fellowship applications, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Holt, Wexler, and Farnam, LLP, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Implementation, 1998-2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Implementation coordinator's manual, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Implementation manual, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Implementation plan, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Improving America's Schools Act service-learning program, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "The learning classroom" [incomplete], 2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Master calendar, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Participating school lists, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Planned change", Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Process documentation, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Role of the Comer facilitator", 2004 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - School lists -- Database changes, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Selected School Development Program surveys, 1999-2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Training list, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Tribal Chiefs Institute, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Academy for Developmentally Centered Education handouts, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 4-7)
  - Academy for Developmentally Centered Education handouts, 2000-2006 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - Academy for Developmentally Centered Education handouts, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Balanced Curriculum Process, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Comer Kids' Academy, 1998-2005 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Developmental Pathways Study Group, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Essentials of Literacy, 2000, undated (Box 7, Folder 5-8)
  - Institutional partnerships -- Drury University, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Leadership development
    - 101 Training
      - Assessment, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
      - Modules, 1995, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      - New York City, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Professional development evaluation reference document, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Workshop packets, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
      - Workshop packets, 2006, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4-7)
    - 102 Training
      - Assessment, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Institutional packet, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Professional development evaluation reference document, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Skills workshop, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
      - Training directory, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Administrators' Leadership Institute, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Comer Project for Change in Education, 1991 April 22-May 3 (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
    - Comer Project for Change in Education, 1991 October 21 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
    - National Academy for Leadership in Education, 1999, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
    - Principals' Academy, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Yale National Leadership Academies, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Regional Training Centers, 1998-2003 (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
  - School and district programs
    - Alabama -- Lowndes County, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - California
      - Bay Area, Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Chula Vista, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - San Diego -- Contracts, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Colorado
      - Colorado Springs, Undated (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
      - Harrison school district, 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
    - Connecticut
      - Groton, 2001-2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Watertown, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - District of Columbia -- Grant correspondence, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Florida -- Miami-Dade, 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Kansas -- Topeka, 1998-2003 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Louisiana -- New Orleans
      - Comer office, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Contracts, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Policy and steering board committee, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Site visits, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Maryland
      - Montgomery County, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
      - Prince George's County
        - Annual retreat, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - Brown, John L. and Antoinette Kellaher pamphlets, 1990-1998 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
        - Demonstration school retreat, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - Demonstration schools, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - "Dr. James Comer and the Comer School Development Program", Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - "Essential understandings for the Comer School Development Program" [draft], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Regional Training Center steering committee, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - Robert Goddard Middle School, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
        - Team guide, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - Training schedule, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous, 1999-2003, undated (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
    - Michigan -- Detroit, 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Mississippi -- Greenwood, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Missouri -- Springfield, 1995-1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - New Jersey
      - Camden, 1999-2001 (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
      - Contracts, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 15, Folder 6-8)
      - "The School Development Program's Essentials of Literacy process and the New Jersey core curriculum standards for language arts literacy", Undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Facilitators workshop, 1999-2002 (Box 15, Folder 10-12)
      - Implementation assessment, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - New Jersey City, 1999-2002 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
      - Neptune Township, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Network of Comer Schools, 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 5-9)
      - Newark, 1999-2002 (Box 16, Folder 10-12)
      - Orange, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Orange, 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
      - West New York, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 2001-2004 (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
    - New York
      - Community School District 13, 1992-1999 (Box 18, Folder 8-11)
      - New York State Education Department, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Westbury County, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - North Carolina
      - Asheville, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Contracts, 1998-2003 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Guilford County Schools
        - "Comer school development process: A school management model", Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - Contracts, 1999-2005 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Cozi, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
        - Cozi correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - Cozi report for Mala Ucell, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 11)
        - Development Pathways viewer's guide, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 12)
        - Dudley High School, 1994-1997 (Box 19, Folder 13)
        - Goals strategic planning, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 14)
        - Hampton Elementary School, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 15)
        - Literature for development, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 16)
        - "A model for systemic reform", 1998 (Box 19, Folder 17)
        - Newsletters, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 18)
        - Oak Hill Elementary School, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 19-20)
        - Operational guide, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Overhead and achievement data, 1996-1998 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Parent team packet, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Parental involvement, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - School climate survey, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Site visit, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - Strategic plan, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 8)
        - Western Guilford High School, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 9)
        - Writing, 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 10-11)
        - Miscellaneous, 1995-1997 (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
      - Lexington, 2002-2006 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
    - Ohio
      - Dayton Public Schools Leadership Institute, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Elyria -- Contract, Undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - South Carolina
      - Contracts, 1999-2000 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Lewisville, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Texas -- Dallas, 1991-1994 (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
    - Virginia
      - Norfolk, 1995-2000 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Portsmouth -- Contracts, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Systemic Implementation Initiative
    - "Impact of systemic reform", Undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Systemic change handbook, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Systemic Reform Conference, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Systemic reform initiative, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Teachers Helping Teachers, Undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-2005 (Box 23, Folder 2-18)
- Research and Evaluation, 1969-2003; Series III
  - School climate reports
    - *** High School, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - *** School -- Parent, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - *** School -- Staff, 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    - *** School -- Student, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Adelphi Elementary -- Parent, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Any school -- Student, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Anyschool America Elementary, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Asheville High -- Student, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Claxton Elementary -- School implementation questionnaire report, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Coeburn Primary -- Staff, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Erwin Open Elementary, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Guilford Middle -- Student, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Middle and elementary -- Student, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - National random sample
      - Elementary, 1995-1996 (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
      - Elementary and middle, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - High, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Middle, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - New Haven
      - General (district-wide)
        - Behavior assessment schedule, elementary and middle schools, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Parent, elementary and middle schools, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - Parent, middle schools, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 3)
        - Report on School Development Program implementation and school climate in School Development Program renewal schools, 1995-1997 (Box 26, Folder 4)
        - Staff, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 5)
        - Staff, elementary and middle schools, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Student, elementary schools, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
        - Student, high schools, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Student, middle schools, 1994-1996 (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
      - Barnard -- Staff, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Career
        - School implementation, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Student, 1995-1997 (Box 27, Folder 8-9)
      - Roberto Clemente
        - Parent, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - Staff, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
        - Student, 1995-1997 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
        - Student, parent, and staff, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Clinton Avenue Language Academy -- Staff, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Cooperative Arts and Humanities High
        - Parent, 1994-1995 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
        - Student, parent, and staff, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Wilbur Cross
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Timothy Dwight Elementary
        - Parent, 1994-1995 (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
        - Student, 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
        - Student, parent, and staff, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - East Rock Community
        - Behavior assessment and schedule for children, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Parent, 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
        - School implementation report, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - Staff, 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
        - Student, 1994-1997 (Box 29, Folder 10-12)
      - Fair Haven Middle
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - School implementation report, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 14)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - Students and staff, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Nathan Hale
        - Parent, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Staff, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Student, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Student, parent, and staff, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - High School in the Community
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Hill Central Elementary
        - Implementation report, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 2)
        - Staff, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 3)
        - Student, 1995-1997 (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
        - Student, parent, and staff, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - James Hillhouse High
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 7)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 8)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Worthington Hooker
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 10)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Prince -- Staff, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Quinnipiac -- Staff, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Jackie Robinson Middle -- Student, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Sheriden Middle
        - Parent, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 4)
        - School implementation report, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 5)
        - Student, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Sound - Staff, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Strong Elementary
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 8)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Troup Middle
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 11)
        - School implementation report, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 12)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 2)
        - Student and Staff, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Truman
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
        - School Implementation Report, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 6)
        - Staff, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
        - Student, 1994-1997 (Box 33, Folder 9-11)
        - Student, parent, and staff, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - West Hills Elementary
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Woodward
        - Parent, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        - Staff, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 11)
        - Student, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Queen's Royal College, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Smith High, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Students, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Student, staff, and parent surveys, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Program evaluation
  - Reference material
    - "Assessment in Connecticut", 1997 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - "Policymakers primer on education research", 2004 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Turning points: Preparing American youth for the twenty-first century", 1989 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "What matters most: Teaching for America's future", 1996 (Box 38, Folder 6)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1983-2000; Series IV
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Associated documentation
    - Index cards describing 1983-1984 videotapes (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Comer retreat, October 6, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Seminar with area curriculum supervisors
    - January 26, 1984, 1 (Box 39)
    - February 2, 1984, 1 (Box 40)
    - Panel on parent participation with Diane Garber, Paul Delgado, and Stephen Signore, 1984 February; 1 (Box 41)
    - Winchester School panel discussion with Mark Palaveri, Lilies Pippert, James P. Comer, and Diane Garber, 1984 March 1; 1 (Box 42)
  - Marjorie Janis in discovery room, sessions 1 (second grade) and 2 (first grade), 1984 May 29; 1 (Box 43)
  - Marjorie Janis in discovery room, sessions 3 (kindergarten) and 4 (fourth grade), 1984 May 29; 1 (Box 44)
  - Marjorie Janis with students, 1984 June 7; 1 (Box 45)
  - James Comer presentation to Connecticut State Department of Education, 1984 July 9-10; 2 (Box 46–47)
  - "Discovery room in the classroom" -- Marjorie Janis, Martin Luther King School
    - Edited version, 1984 November; 1 (Box 48)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 48U)
    - Session 1, October 5 and Janis showing program materials, October 23, 1984; 1 (Box 49)
    - Opening -- A. Small, Pachesca, ribbon cutting, and children playing in strawberry discovery lab, 1984 October 19; 1 (Box 50)
  - Seminar with area curriculum supervisors, 1985 March 15; 1 (Box 51)
  - "Social change and schools: How to promote child development" -- Kindergarten workshop at East Rock School, July 1, 1985
    - Edited version of James P. Comer's presentation, 1985 September; 1 (Box 52)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 52U)
    - Unedited version including question and answer and Diane Garber's presentation, 1985; 2 (Box 53–54)
  - ERIN workshop -- East Rock School -- Diane Garber, 1985 July 8; 1 (Box 55)
  - Child Development for Teachers -- School change -- James Comer, Jan Stocklinski, 1985 September 19; 1 (Box 56)
  - Presentation to Prince George's County -- Benton Harbor, Urban Coalition [volume problem], 1986 February 3; 2 (Box 58–59)
  - Parent-teacher presentation to Prince George's County administrators, New Haven -- Teachers and parent volunteer from King and Brennan Schools, 1986 February 4; 1 (Box 60)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 60U)
  - Macy group training for sophomore advisors
    - James Comer, 1986 September 13; 1 (Box 62)
  - James Comer, 1987 March 17; 1 (Box 65)
  - Debriefing with San Francisco, White Plains, Benton Harbor, and Norfolk, Arkansas, 1987 March 18; 1 (Box 66)
  - Comer-Rockefeller retreat, Sarasota, Florida
    - Interview with Principal Fitz-Harris and B-Roll, Gocio Elementary School, 1989 November 15; 1 (Box 67)
    - B-Roll at Gocio Elementary School and interview with Principal C. T. Cooley, 1989 November 15; 1 (Box 68)
    - Interview with Principal Cooley and Gocio meeting, 1989 November 15; 1 (Box 69)
    - Gocio planning meeting, 1989 November 15; 1 (Box 70)
    - Interview with Earl Watts and Tuttle School B-Roll, 1989 November 16; 1 (Box 71)
    - Tuttle Elementary School Southside Community meeting with Principal John Spielman, 1989 November 16; 1 (Box 72)